Guide to the John Randolph Papers WAG.255
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Subjects, 1940-1999
  - Issues: Vietnam, 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Issues: Women, 1952-1953, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Itinerary for JR, May 9, 1996-Jul 15, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Kazan, Elia, Lifetime Achievement Oscar: Randolph Statement and Related Materials, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom, Aug 28, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Membership and Business Cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Military Service, 1941-1945 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Neighborhood Artists, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - New York Apartment, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Patterson, William L. Foundation (JR and SC, founding members), 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - People's Weekly World Banquet (Chicago), 1992, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Phone Lists, Contact Sheets, Date Book, 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Erwin Piscator: Memorial Service, Jun 4, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - John Reed Centennial Celebration, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Paul Robeson: Celebrations, Articles and Related Materials, 1958-1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Screen Actors Guild (SAG): 1971 Elections and Related Materials (includes John Gavin letter), 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - SAG: Committees (includes Legacy and Conservatory Committees), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - SAG: Delegation to the German Democratic Republic (GDR), 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - SAG: General, 1972-1999 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - SAG: Strike, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Showbiz by Maxwell Glanville, Volume 4, Number 4, Apr 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Slouching towards a National Theater" in New Federal One, Apr 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Supreme Court Decisions: Quinn and Watkins, 1954, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Theatre and Human Rights: Panel with SC, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Theatre People for Peace", 1962 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "This Is the Year" (also known as "From Chungking to Frisco"), Sheet Music, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "Trial of Traitors" Meeting Speech by Allan Sloane, Jan 29, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - War Department Employment Records for SC, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Women Strike for Peace, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Series III: Productions and Professional Activities, 1938-1999
  - After the Fall (play) with JR and SC, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - All Aboard! by Ben Bengal (play), undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - American Clock by Arthur Miller (play), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - An Evening's Frost (play) at Theatre De Lys, University of Michigan and Possible USSR Tour, 1965-1967, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Animal Kingdom (play) at Bucks County Playhouse, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Herbert Aptheker and the Negro Struggle: Excerpts for Readings, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Back in the Race (play), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Ballad of the Winter Soldiers (play), 1964 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Barsky (Dr. Edward) Tribute Dinner (script), Feb 24, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Barroom Monks (play script) with SC, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Beryl Isaac, Miracle of Hashno Rabo, Tit for Tat, Yom Kippur Scandal (play scripts) by Sholem Aleichem, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Born Yesterday (play), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Brecht, (play script, excerpts from his work) presented at Columbia University with Frederick Ewen and the "Angry Arts" Peace Program, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Broadway Bound (play): Broadway and on Tour, 1986-1995 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Broadway Bound: Letters of Congratulation during Broadway Run, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Broadway Bound: Letters of Congratulation during Broadway Run, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Brotherhood on Broadway (reading, script), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Elizabeth Barrett and Robert Browning: Excerpts from Letters, Sonnets and Poems, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Cable Car Murder (television movie), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - California Wine (play) with SC, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Camera Three (television program) with JR and SC, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Carnegie Hall program on the Rosenbergs (script), undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Case of Libel (play), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Cause of it All (excerpts) by Leo Tolstoy, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Celebration with Ossie Davis and Ruby Dee and Friends, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Ceremonies in Dark Old Men: Program and Clippings, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Chekov notes, including "Olga Knipper Chekhov Speaks", undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Chicken Soup with Barley (play, script) by Arnold Wesker with SC, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Children of Sanchez: Book Report-type Presentation, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Children's Program Outline, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Christy (play) with SC, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Cid (radio, script), 1938 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Comeback Little Sheba (play) with JR as the Milkman, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Command Decision (play), 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Concert Readings with JR and SC, 1950-1962 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Concert Readings with JR and SC, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Conquest of the Planet of the Apes (film), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Contracts: JR, 1941-1973 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Contracts: SC, 1963-1973 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Conversation at Midnight (play), 1964 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Cowboys (movie): SC costars with John Wayne, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Created Equal (Federal Theatre Project play), 1938 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Current Rage (play) with SC at the Ensemble Studio Theatre, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Day They Shot John Lennon (play), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Death of a Salesman (play) at Arlington Park Theatre, Arlington Heights, Illinois, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Death of Innocence (television movie), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Dictionary's Party (short story) by Martin Weldon, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Dramatic Workshop at New School/Erwin Piscator, Director: Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Electra (excerpts) by Euripides, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Emma Lazurus (sic) (excerpts), undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Ensemble Studio Theatre, 1973-1999 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Fair Game (play) with SC, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fairleigh Dickenson University Class, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Family Kovack (television movie) with SC, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Family Rico (television movie), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - [Jules] Feiffer cartoons, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fever for Life (play), 1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - First Day in America (play) by Yuri Suhl (includes poem And the Earth Rebelled from 1954), undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fishke the Lame (excerpts) by Mendele Mocher Seforim, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Field (movie), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Freedomways Magazine presents An Evening of Dramatic Arts, Feb 22, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Front Page (play), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Going Home (movie), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Golden State (play), 1950 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Good Night! Monologue on Child Discipline for the PTA, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Guys and Dolls (musical), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Hannukah Money (excerpts) with JR and SC, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Henry IV, Part I (scene for two men), undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Here Dies Another Day (AFI movie), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Hotel Manor Inn (movie), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - House of Bernarda Alba (play) with SC, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - In the Matter of J. Robert Oppenheimer (play), 1968 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Indian Centennial Song by Chief Dan George, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Inherit the Wind (play): National Tour with Melvyn Douglas, 1956-1957, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Introductions, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Introductions to Jewish Materials, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Investigator: A Political Satire in Documentary Form, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Ivory Tower (play), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Jerome, V. J.: Vignettes from Unstill Waters, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Jewish Currents (Morris Schappes, Editor) Annual Concerts with JR and SC, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - "Jewish Wife" from Private Life of the Master Race (play) by Bertolt Brecht, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Juno and the Paycock (excerpts) by Sean O'Casey, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - "Kasrilevka" from The Schtetl by Sholem Aleichem, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Ladies in Waiting (play) at the Negro Ensemble Company with SC, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Lamp Unto My Feet episode "O the Chimneys" (television), Oct 15, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Lecture: Method Acting vs. Classical, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Life with Father (play) in Greenville, South Carolina (includes copy of program from original New York production), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Light Up the Sky (Play), 1959 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Line (play) by Israel Horovitz from Acrobats and Line, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Little Foxes (excerpts) by Lillian Hellman, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Little Murders (movie), 1971 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Little Rooster and the Turkish Sultan (play/script), undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Living Flame (play), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Local 1199: Theatre Presentations and Film Works, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Lone Rider (radio script), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Look Back, Mrs. Lot by Ephrain Kishon (excerpts include "Jewish Poker"), undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Lost in the Stars: Scene between Jarvis and Stephen, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Lysistrata (play excerpt): Scene for Two Women, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Macbeth (play excerpt): Scene for a Man and a Women, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Mademoiselle Colombe (play) with SC, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Madrid 1937: VALB 60th Anniversary Dinner, Apr 21, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Magic Mountain (play script) by Thomas Mann adapted by Frederic Ewen, Phoebe Brand, and John Randolph, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Magic Mountain (play): Correspondence, Programs, Notes, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Mating Dance (play) with SC, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Medicine Show (play), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Midsummer Night's Dream (play excerpt) for American Academy Class, undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Mission Impossible (television episode): Call Sheet, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - "Mitzvah" from The Old Country by Sholem Aleichem, undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Modern Children (play) from the Sholem Aleichem Stories, undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Mother Courage and Her Children (play), 1963 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Motive (play), 1970 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - My Brother Mike ([student?] film), undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) with JR and SC, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Native Son (play): National Tour Starring Canada Lee, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - "Negro History" Scripts and Related Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - New Theatre for Now, Mark Taper Forum, Los Angeles, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Nihilists (play script): Master Copy, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Nihilists (play script): Third Draft "for Reference," Incomplete, undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Nourish the Beast (play and television movie), 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Number One (movie): Working Title Pro, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Oh, Pioneers (play) with SC, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - One Foot in America (various stories) by Yuri Suhl, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Our Faces, Our Words (excerpts) by Lillian Smith for a Program on Civil Rights, undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Our Greek Experience: A Synthesis of Group Discussions Led by Professors Karl H. Niebyl, Alban Winspear and Others with National Guardian Travelers in Greece, Jun 1966 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Page from the Song of Songs by Sholem Aleichem, undated (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Paint Your Wagon (musical), 1951 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Passover Swindle by Sholem Aleichem, undated (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Peddler and the Dodo Bird (play): Clippings, Correspondence and Related Materials (includes correspondence with playwright Emanuel Fried), 1963-1970 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Peer Gynt (play), 1951 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Philadelphia Drama Guild (John Randolph, Artistic Consultant), 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Philadelphia Drama Guild: Death of a Salesman, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Philadelphia Drama Guild: The Little Foxes, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Philadelphia Drama Guild: The Rose Tattoo, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Philadelphia Drama Guild: The Taming of the Shrew, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Poems: Bertolt Brecht, undated (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Poems: Heinrich Heine's "Donna Clara", undated (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Poems: "Lullaby for a South African Child of Apartheid", undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Poems: Pablo Neruda, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Poems: Beulah Richardson, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Poems: Selections from Carl Sandburg's The People, Yes, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Poems: "Years of the Modern" from Walt Whitman's Leaves of Grass, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man and The Barroom Monks): Plays with SC; JR is one of the adaptors of Portrait; Shamrock Company/Paul Libin, Producer with Round Table Review and Madeline Lee at the Martinique Theatre, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Possessed (play script), undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Prelude to a Kiss (play), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Present Tense (play) with SC, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Pretty Poison (movie), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Private Hicks (play script) by Albert Maltz, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Pygmalion (play), undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Quartette Productions with JR and SC, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Radio Show Reviews, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Rap on Race (play) with SC, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Readings, 1961-1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Rescue (television script): Philco Television Playhouse, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Respectful Prostitute (play), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Riders to the Sea (play), undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Rimers of Eldritch (monologues), undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Room Service (play), 1946 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Round Table Review by/with Phoebe Brand and John Randolph with Commentary by Dr. Frederic Ewen, 1958-1963 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Ruby McCollum for LA Theatre Works, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Salt of the Earth (excerpts), undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Saville Playhouse Summer Season, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Scenes from the Works of Sean O'Casey (play): Theatre 1199, [1964?] (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Scenes from Uncle Vanya, Peer Gynt, The Lost Weekend, Important of Being Earnest, Parian or the Outcast, Bourgomaster, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Script Sides: All Summer Long, Goldberg, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Scuff (movie): JR invested in, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Seagull (play) with SC, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Seconds (movie): Original Opening and Re-Release, 1965-1966, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Serpico (movie), 1973 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Shakespeare Comedies: Scenes for One Man and One Woman, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Shakespeare Monologues, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Short plays about Elizabeth Gurley Flynn and Mother Bloor, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Silver Cord (play) at Equity Library Theatre, [1947?] (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Siren and Chameleon (play scripts) by Anton Chekhov, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Song of the Fire Ovens (play script) by Peter Weiss, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Sound of Music (musical), 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Stage for Action: Satire Matinee, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Stage for Action Scripts: Talk in Darkness by Malvin Wald; You're Next by Arthur Miller, 1939, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - String of Pearls (play) with JR and SC at Sholem Aleichem Club, Philadelphia, PA, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Subversives for Medicare: Script of a Skit by Art Buchwald, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Talent (play), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Tartuffe (play excerpt): Scene for Two Men and a Woman, undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Technicians All: Army Script Done at Chanute Field, [1940s] (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Tevya and His Daughters (play) with JR and SC (includes copy of Dramatists Play Service script), 1959 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Theatrical Programs, 1939-1966 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - There Was a Crooked Man (movie), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - They Call Me Alien (poem), undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - This Town: A Play of Manners by Sidney Blumenthal in Backstage West, Apr 4, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Time of Your Life (play), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Too True to Be Good (play scene) by George Bernard Shaw, undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Toys in the Attic (play) with SC, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Transit Theater, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Tribute to Erwin Piscator, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Triple Play (play) Produced by the Theatre Guild, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Unknown Chekhov (play script) Adapted and Arranged by Frederic Ewen, Phoebe Brand and John Randolph, undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - "Useful Quotes", undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Vanka (play scene) by Chekhov, undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Veterans Peace Conference (script) Held at Madison Square Garden, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Victors (NYU Graduate Student Film) by Doro Bachrach, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Visit (play), 1958 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Waltz of the Toreadors (play), 1973 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Ward Number Six (play script) by Anton Chekhov, Adapted by Frederic Ewen, Phoebe Brand and John Randolph, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Warsaw Ghetto (monologue), undated (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Watch on the Rhine (play scene), undated (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Way of the World (play excerpts), undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - We Hold These Truths (play script): Adaptation, undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Weizmann (Chaim) Dinner: Script and Correspondence, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Why America Deserves Eisenhower (poem), 1950s (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Wooden Dish (play), 1955 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Workers Theatre (documentary), 1998 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Working Theatre, 1996-1999 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - World of Sholem Aleichem (play) with SC and occasionally JR, 1953-1965 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Young Hack and His Girl (play scene), undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Israel Zangwill (performance script): Dreamer of the Ghetto, undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Israel Zangwill (script): King of the Schnorrers, undated (Box 6, Folder 78)
- Series IV: Oversize Material, 1955
  - Scrapbook on HUAC Hearings, Compiled for a Benefit at the Stella Adler Studio in Los Angeles, California, Jun 12, 1997 (Box Tamiment Shared MSOS001)
  - Variety ad re: AFTRA member resolution, Jul 27, 1955 (Box Tamiment Shared MSOS001)
- Series V: Photographs and Recordings, 1944-2003 (Box Tamiment Shared OS009, Folder 1)
  - John Randolph Photographs, 1944-1970 (Box 7)
  - Audio and Videorecordings, 1970-2003 (Box 8)